Guide to the Edmond Pauker Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Business Files, 1898-1960; Series II; 14.6; (36 boxes)
  - CLIENT FILES
    - Körmendi, Ferenc
      - Gale Winds from the East: statement, 1952 Feb 24 (Box 28, Folder 651)
      - The Seventh Trumpet: statements, 1953 Jan (Box 28, Folder 652)
      - Years of the Eclipse (book): statements, 1951-52 (Box 28, Folder 653)
    - Körmendi, Ferenc and Steven Vas
      - This Is Your Confession: statements, 1951 Jun 22 (Box 28, Folder 654)
    - Kornitzer, Bela
      - American Fathers and Sons (book)
        - Contracts, 1951, 1953 (Box 28, Folder 655)
        - Statements, 1951, 1953 (Box 28, Folder 656)
    - Kosztolányi, Dezsö
      - The Bloody Poet: contract, 1927 (Box 28, Folder 657)
    - Lahn, Ilse and Walter Firner
      - Happy Island: contract, 1940 Jul 11 (Box 28, Folder 658)
    - Lakatos, Ladislaus
      - Filléres gyors and A királyné: contract, 1934 Dec 21 (Box 28, Folder 659)
    - Lampel, Peter Martin
      - Before the Dawn: contract, 1942 May 15 (Box 28, Folder 660)
    - Langer, Frantisek
      - Die Bekehrung des Ferdis Pistory ( Obraceni Ferdyse Pistory ): contract, 1935 Nov 13 (Box 28, Folder 661)
      - Peripherie
        - Contracts, 1937-40 (Box 28, Folder 662)
        - Correspondence, 1953-54 (Box 28, Folder 663)
    - László, Aladár
      - Contracts: general, 1935 (Box 28, Folder 664)
      - A becsületes megtaláló: contracts, 1932 (Box 28, Folder 665)
      - Ringstrasse #3: contracts, 1934 Mar (Box 28, Folder 666)
      - A Woman's Past ( Egy nö akinek multja van ): contracts, 1935-43 (Box 28, Folder 667)
        Adapted by Keith Miller and by Barre Dunbar
    - László, Miklós
      - Contracts: general, 1938-40 (Box 28, Folder 668)
      - Correspondence: general, 1939-51 (Box 28, Folder 669)
        Incl: Hume Cronyn
      - The Happiest Man: contract, 1941 Feb (Box 29, Folder 670)
      - St. Lazare's Pharmacy: contracts, 1940-55 (Box 29, Folder 671)
        Incl: contracts for adaptations by William Ford Manley and Eddie Dowling
      - The Shop Around the Corner ( Illatszertár ): contracts, 1938-58 (Box 29, Folder 672)
    - Lauden, Thomas
      - Sub-Lieutenant: contract, 1936 Oct 14 (Box 29, Folder 673)
    - Lavery, Emmet
      - Monsignor's Hour: contracts, 1936 Jun (Box 29, Folder 674)
    - Laytha, Edgar
      - North Again for Gold [book?]: contracts, 1939-40 (Box 29, Folder 675)
    - Lederer, Charlotte
      - Eagle's Quest ( Lift Up Your Heart ) (novel): contracts, 1939 June 2 (Box 29, Folder 676)
    - Lehar, Franz
      - "The White Dove" (musical composition): contract, 1934 Mar 30 (Box 29, Folder 677)
        See also: Victor Leon and Leo Walther Stein: The Merry Widow ( Die lustige Witwe ), Box 29, folder 691
    - Lengyel, Menyhért (Melchior)
      - Contract: general, 1938 June 14 (Box 29, Folder 678)
      - Forever Young: statements, 1952 (Box 29, Folder 679)
      - The Genius (formerly entitled Kean or Portrait of an Actor )
        - Contracts, 1952, 1956 (Box 29, Folder 680)
        - Statement, 1952 Jan 17 (Box 29, Folder 681)
      - Rhamses or Caruso ( Caruso contra Rhamses ): contracts, 1934, 1937 (Box 29, Folder 682)
      - Silk Stockings ( Ninotchka )
        See also: István Tamás: Moscow-Paris and Return, Box 40, folder 691
        - Contract, 1955 Dec 29 (Box 29, Folder 683)
        - Correspondence, 1954-57 (Box 29, Folder 684-685)
        - Statements, 1953-58 (Box 29, Folder 686)
        - Playbill and programs, 1954, [1955] (Box 29, Folder 687)
        - Reviews and publicity, 1955-56 (Box 29, Folder 688)
          See also: Oversize, Box 52, folder 1259
      - Sparrow ( Spatz ): contracts, 1932, 1934 (Box 29, Folder 689)
    - Lenormand, Henri-René
      - Asie: contracts, 1932 (Box 29, Folder 690)
    - Lenz, Leo
      See: Leo Perutz, Box 36, folder 867
    - Leon, Victor and Leo Walther Stein
      - The Merry Widow ( Die lustige Witwe ): contracts, 1922-30, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 691)
    - Leslie, Paul
      - Satyr: contracts, 1936 (Box 29, Folder 692)
    - Lestyán, ---- and ---- Vaszary
      - Potyautas: contract, 1931 Jul 15 (Box 29, Folder 693)
    - Letraz, Jean de and Stella Adorján
      - Maczkó úr ( Bichon ): contract, 1939 Mar 31 (Box 29, Folder 694)
    - Lewis, Herbert Clyde
      - Contracts: general, 1937-43 (Box 30, Folder 695)
      - "Conjurers' Shop" [story?]: contract, 1943 Apr 1 (Box 30, Folder 696)
      - "Hot Seat Surprise" (story): contract, 1937 Jun 9 (Box 30, Folder 697)
      - "The Old Neighborhood" [story?]: contracts, 1943 Mar 26 (Box 30, Folder 698)
      - "Surprise for the Boys" (story): contracts, 1940 Sep 21 (Box 30, Folder 699)
    - Lewis, Herbert Clyde and Chester Erskin
      - Two-Faced Quilligan: contracts, 1942-43 (Box 30, Folder 700)
    - Lewis, Herbert Clyde and Joseph Quentin Riznik
      - Love at 300: contract, 1936 Sep 3 (Box 30, Folder 701)
    - Lewis, Herbert Clyde and Louis Weitzenkorn
      - Name Your Poison: contracts, 1936 Aug 12 (Box 30, Folder 702)
    - Lichtenberg, Wilhelm
      - Ein Koenigreich für eine Frau: contract, 1932 Mar 31 (Box 30, Folder 703)
    - Liebson, Lawrence S.
      - For This We Fight: contracts, 1941 Oct 31 (Box 30, Folder 704)
    - Liszt, Rudolph G.
      - Contract: general, 1937 May 30 (Box 30, Folder 705)
    - Lonsdale, Frederick
      - Aren't We All: contracts, 1930 May 21 (Box 30, Folder 706)
    - Lothar, Rudolph
      - Ist den das so Wichtig: contracts, 1930 Feb 21 (Box 30, Folder 707)
    - Lothar, Rudolph and Erno Sebesi
      - Collision: contracts, 1930-31 (Box 30, Folder 708)
    - Lothar, ---- and ---- Lernet-Holenia
      - Die Frau in der Wolke: contracts, 1930 (Box 30, Folder 709)
    - Mahl, William
      - All Will Change: contract, 1939 May 3 (Box 30, Folder 710)
    - Mannheimer, Albert and Frederick Kohner
      - Stalin Allee
        - Contracts, 1956-58 (Box 30, Folder 711)
        - Copyright registration, 1957 Jan 18 (Box 30, Folder 712)
        - Correspondence, 1956-59 (Box 30, Folder 713-715)
        - Statements, 1956-57 (Box 30, Folder 716)
        - Program, 1956 (Box 30, Folder 717)
        - Reviews and publicity, 1957 Jan 18 (Box 30, Folder 718)
    - Mantica, Margit
      - It Started With Spinach: contracts, 1941 Nov 27 (Box 30, Folder 719)
        Incl: contract for collaboration with Rosalind Ivan
    - Marion, Lee and H. Eugenie Tyroler
      - Sweet Fire: contract, 1947 Nov 20 (Box 30, Folder 720)
    - Martin, Ben
      - Rogues March: contracts, 1942-44 (Box 30, Folder 721)
      - Sing Cuckoo: contract, 1946 Jul 8 (Box 30, Folder 722)
    - Martos, Ferenc
      - Princess Charming: contracts, 1930-31 (Box 30, Folder 723)
    - Masefield, John
      - Sard Harker (novel)
        - Contracts, 1956-57, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 724)
        - Correspondence, 1956-58, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 725-727)
    - Mayer, Louise Marie and Arthur Rundt
      - Disraeli [book?]: contracts, 1932 May (Box 31, Folder 728)
    - Menzies, Archie N.
      - The Astonished Ostrich: contracts, 1939-46, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 729)
    - Merivale, George Clifford
      - King's Evidence: contract, 1938 Jan 29 (Box 31, Folder 730)
    - Mihály, Eisemann
      - "Tango Argentine" ("Lesz maga juszt is az enyém") (musical composition): contract, 1931 (Box 31, Folder 731)
    - Millard, Oscar and Edmond Wolf
      - Whenever I Remember ( The Magic Lantern ): contract, 1943 Nov 15 (Box 31, Folder 732)
    - Miller, Patsy Ruth
      - Windy Hill: contracts, 1945-46 (Box 31, Folder 733)
        Incl: contract for revision by Mark Hanna
    - Mitchell, Fanny Todd
      - The Eligible Man: contract, 1941 Dec 10 (Box 31, Folder 734)
      - Louisi-Ann ( Thoika ): contracts, 1943 Oct 18 (Box 31, Folder 735)
        For music by Robert Stoltz
    - Mitchell, Ronald
      - Alfred: contract, 1956 May 24 (Box 31, Folder 736)
      - Dan Owen and the Angel Joe: contracts, 1948-49 (Box 31, Folder 737)
      - Dan Owen's Afternoon [book?]: contract, 1947 Feb 26 (Box 31, Folder 738)
      - Design for a November Night [book?]: contract, 1946 Apr 12 (Box 31, Folder 739)
      - The Kindest People: contracts, 1945 (Box 31, Folder 740)
    - Molnár, Ferenc
      - Contracts: general, 1923-55 (Box 31, Folder 741)
      - Copyrights, 1941-52, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 742)
      - Correspondence: general, 1941-60, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 743-749)
        See also: Bass & Harlow, Box 44, folder 1075
      - Menu, from dinner [in honor of Molnár?] at the Ritz Carlton, New York, 1927 Dec 18 (Box 31, Folder 750)
      - Obituaries, 1952 Apr (Box 31, Folder 751)
      - Statements: general, 1952-54, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 752)
      - Arthur ( Somebody )
        Title varies. Incl: contract for adaptation by P. G. Wodehouse
        - Contracts, 1931-55 (Box 31, Folder 753)
        - Correspondence, 1953-55 (Box 31, Folder 754)
          Incl: Charles Coburn, Lawrence Langner, Ginger Rogers, Harold Winston
        - Statements, 1953-57 (Box 31, Folder 755)
        - Programs, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 756)
        - Reviews and publicity, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 757)
      - The Blue Danube (formerly Delilah )
        - Contracts, 1937, 1952 (Box 32, Folder 758)
        - Correspondence, 1952-54 (Box 32, Folder 759)
        - Statements, 1952-58 (Box 32, Folder 760)
      - "The Blue-Eyed Lady" (story)
        - Contracts, 1942, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 761)
        - Statements, 1950-56 (Box 32, Folder 762)
      - The Captain of St Margaret (novel)
        - Contracts, 1951 (Box 32, Folder 763)
        - Statements, 1951-52 (Box 32, Folder 764)
      - Carnival: contracts, 1938 Sep 1 (Box 32, Folder 765)
      - Carousel
        Richard Rodgers' and Oscar Hammerstein's adaptation of Molnár's Liliom
        - Contracts, 1943-55 (Box 32, Folder 766)
        - Correspondence, 1945-56 (Box 32, Folder 767-770)
        - Statements, 1949-59 (Box 32, Folder 771-772)
        - Reviews and publicity, 1949 (Box 32, Folder 773)
      - Delicate Story
        - Contracts, 1940-56 (Box 32, Folder 774)
        - Statements, 1951-56 (Box 32, Folder 775)
        - Review, 1954 May 1 (Box 32, Folder 776)
      - Farewell, My Heart: contract, 1944 Nov 10 (Box 32, Folder 777)
      - Game of Hearts (formerly entitled Pit-A-Pat ): contracts, 1946-47 (Box 32, Folder 778)
        Incl: contract for English text by P. G. Wodehouse
      - The Good Fairy
        - Contracts, 1930-55 (Box 32, Folder 779)
        - Correspondence, 1955-56, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 780-781)
        - Statements, 1950-56 (Box 33, Folder 782)
        - Reviews and publicity, 1956 (Box 33, Folder 783)
      - Great Love: contracts, 1935-37 (Box 33, Folder 784)
      - The Guardsman
        - Contracts, 1924-55 (Box 33, Folder 785)
        - Correspondence, 1950-52 (Box 33, Folder 786)
        - Statements, 1947-57 (Box 33, Folder 787)
        - Publicity, 1950-51 (Box 33, Folder 788)
      - Heavenly and Earthly Love
        - Contracts, 1958 Feb 26 (Box 33, Folder 789)
        - Statement, 1958 Aug 11 (Box 33, Folder 790)
      - The King's Maid
        - Contracts, 1941 (Box 33, Folder 791)
          Incl: contract for English text by Francis Edward Faragoh
        - Financial statements, 1941 Dec (Box 33, Folder 792)
        - Review, 1941 Dec (Box 33, Folder 793)
      - The Last Role ( The Emperor ): contracts, 1942-43 (Box 33, Folder 794)
        Incl: contract for English text by Arthur Richman
      - The Lawyer ( A doktor úr ): contracts, 1926-46 (Box 33, Folder 795)
        Incl: contract for adaptation by Alexander King
      - Liliom
        - Contracts, 1921-56 (Box 33, Folder 796-797)
          Incl: contracts for adaptation by Benjamin F. Glazer
        - Correspondence, 1953-54 (Box 33, Folder 798-799)
        - Statements, 1951-59 (Box 33, Folder 800-801)
        - Statements, 1951-59 (Box 34, Folder 802-803)
        - Review, 1923 Jun 20 (Box 34, Folder 804)
      - "Love Makes Me Sick" (film story): contracts, 1945-46 (Box 34, Folder 805)
        Based on Daddy Is a Wolf by Joseph Pasternak
      - Marshal: contracts, 1941 (Box 34, Folder 806)
      - A Matter of Husbands: contract, 1935 Aug 23 (Box 34, Folder 807)
      - Miracle in the Mountains ( Csoda a hegyek közt )
        - Contracts, 1933-46 (Box 34, Folder 808)
        - Statements, 1947 (Box 34, Folder 809)
      - Music Playing Angel (novel): contracts, 1933 Aug (Box 34, Folder 810)
      - Noah's Ark: contracts, 1943-44 (Box 34, Folder 811)
      - Nuptial Song: contract, 1944 Sep 20 (Box 34, Folder 812)
      - Olympia
        See also: Edward Chodorov: The Spa, Box 20, folder 419
        - Contracts, 1929, 1939 (Box 34, Folder 813)
        - Correspondence, 1953, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 814)
        - Statements, 1950-56 (Box 34, Folder 815)
      - One, Two, Three
        - Contracts, 1929, 1958 (Box 34, Folder 816)
        - Correspondence, 1950, 1953 (Box 34, Folder 817)
        - Correspondence, 1953-56 (Box 34, Folder 818-821)
          Incl: Irving Lazar
      - Öszi utazás (novel): contract, 1939 Jan 10 (Box 34, Folder 822)
        For translation by Emil Lengyel
      - The Paul Street Boys ( A Pál utcai fiúk ) (novel): contracts, 1937 Mar 1 (Box 34, Folder 823)
        For play by Alexander Hevesi based on Molnár's novel of the same title
      - The Play's the Thing ( Játék a kastélyban )
        - Contracts, 1924-58 (Box 34, Folder 824-825)
          Incl: contracts for the English adaptation by P. G. Wodehouse
        - Correspondence, 1951-54 (Box 34, Folder 826-827)
        - Statements, 1948-58 (Box 34, Folder 828-829)
      - Portrait of an Actor: contract, 1950 Nov 20 (Box 35, Folder 830)
      - Rabok (novel): contract, 1925 Jun 25 (Box 35, Folder 831)
      - Riviera: contracts, 1928-1949 (Box 35, Folder 832)
        Incl: contracts for an adaptation by Edward Chodorov
      - Romantic Comedies, Eight Plays (book)
        - Contracts, 1951 (Box 35, Folder 833)
        - Reviews, 1952 (Box 35, Folder 834)
      - The Swan
        - Contracts, 1922-55 (Box 35, Folder 835-836)
          See also: Oversize, Box 52, folder 1260
        - Copyright, 1925 Jul 11
          See: Oversize, Box 52, folder 1261
        - Statements, 1950-54 (Box 35, Folder 837)
      - The Tale of the Wolf ( A farkas )
        - Contracts, 1946, 1950 (Box 35, Folder 838)
        - Statement, 1950 Sep 26 (Box 35, Folder 839)
      - There Is a Play Tonight: contracts, 1940-42 (Box 35, Folder 840)
      - The Unknown Girl ( Az ismeretlen lány ): contracts, 1934-37 (Box 35, Folder 841)
      - Violet: statements, 1952-53 (Box 35, Folder 842)
      - Waxworks: contract, 1942 Apr 13 (Box 35, Folder 843)
        For English text by Arthur Richman
      - The Witch: contract, 1936 Sep 22 (Box 35, Folder 844)
    - Móricz, Zsigmond
      - Be Good Forever ( Légy jó mindhalálig ): contracts, 1936 (Box 35, Folder 845)
    - Morrill, Katherine
      - And So, Farewell
        - Contracts, 1955-57 (Box 35, Folder 846)
        - Correspondence, 1957-58, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 847)
        - Statements, 1956-58 (Box 35, Folder 848)
        - Programs, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 849)
        - Reviews and publicity, 1957-58 (Box 35, Folder 850)
    - Morros, Boris
      - My Ten Years As a Counter Spy (book): contracts, 1957 (Box 35, Folder 851)
    - Mussolini, Benito and Giovacchino Forzano
      - One Hundred Days ( Campo di Maggio ): contracts, 1931-34 (Box 35, Folder 852)
    - Myers, Robert Manson
      - Correspondence: general, 1953-56 (Box 35, Folder 853-854)
      - From Beowulf to Virginia Woolf (book)
        - Contract, 1952 Feb 14 (Box 36, Folder 855)
        - Statements, 1952-59 (Box 36, Folder 856)
    - Nash, Alden and Peter Berneis
      - A Certain Miss Jones: contract, 1945 May 8 (Box 36, Folder 857)
    - Neumann, Alfred
      - Der Patriot: contracts, 1943 (Box 36, Folder 858)
        Contract with Clifford Odets for dramatic rights
    - Nevin, Hardwick and Henry James Forman
      - Dr. Nostradamus: contract, 1942 Nov (Box 36, Folder 859)
    - North, Clyde, Albert C. Fuller & Jack T. Nelson
      - Remote Control: contracts, 1929-35 (Box 36, Folder 860)
    - Oesterreicher, Rudolf and Adolf Schütz
      - Die Marschallin: contracts, 1936-37 (Box 36, Folder 861)
        Incl: contract for adaptation by Victor Victor (Marshall George)
    - Osborn, Paul
      - The Vinegar Tree: contract, 1931 Jan 31 (Box 36, Folder 862)
    - Pakots, Jozsef
      - Krizis: contract, 1922 Aug 11 (Box 36, Folder 863)
      - A tigris: contract, 1922 Jan 17 (Box 36, Folder 864)
    - Pauker, John
      - "They Walk in the Sun" (story): contract, 1940 Jul 18 (Box 36, Folder 865)
    - Paulay, Elisabeth Cerrutti de
      - I Sat Next to Them (book): contracts, 1948-49 (Box 36, Folder 866)
    - Perutz, Leo
      - My Wife's Perfume ( Das Parfum meiner Frau ): contracts, 1930 (Box 36, Folder 867)
      - Die Reise nach Pressburg: contracts, 1931-34 (Box 36, Folder 868)
    - Perutz, Leo and Hans Adler
      - Tomorrow's a Holiday: contracts, 1935 (Box 36, Folder 869)
    - Phillips, Rufus
      - Off the Record :ùiontracts, 1940 (Box 36, Folder 870)
      - Evolving Universe [book?]: statement, 1954 May 14 (Box 36, Folder 871)
    - Plimmer, Denis
      - Land's End: statements, 1951-57 (Box 36, Folder 872)
    - Pressburger, Emmerich
      - "Zweimel Sylvester" (story): contract, 1935 Feb 9 (Box 36, Folder 873)
        Contract with Emery Kanark to adapt the story for film
    - Preston, Randolph
      - Jenepher's Wooing: contracts, 1942, 1944 (Box 36, Folder 874)
    - Puder, Sandor
      - Allapota Kielegito (book): contract, 1936 Sep 17 (Box 36, Folder 875)
      - Condition Satisfactory (book): contract, 1938 Apr 1 (Box 36, Folder 876)
    - Quin, Sherland
      - Here's To Us: contracts, 1943-44 (Box 36, Folder 877)
    - Raggio, Enrico
      - Die letzte Nacht des Don Ortega: contracts, 1935, 1940 (Box 36, Folder 878)
        Incl: contracts for adaptations by Rosalind Ivan and Walter L. Greene
    - Rand, Ayn
      - The Night of January 16th
        - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 36, Folder 879)
        - Statements, 1946, 1953 (Box 36, Folder 880)
    - Raphaelson, Samson
      - Accent on Youth: contracts, 1935-36 (Box 36, Folder 881)
    - Reed, Mark
      - Yes, My Darling Daughter
        - Contract, 1958 Jun 6 (Box 36, Folder 882)
        - Correspondence, 1956-59 (Box 36, Folder 883)
        - Statements, 1956, 1959 (Box 36, Folder 884)
    - Reeves, Theodore
      - Still Life: contract, 1935 Nov 18 (Box 36, Folder 885)
    - Reich, Richard
      - Correspondence: general, 1954-58 (Box 36, Folder 886-890)
      - Come In Little Girl: contract, 1943 May 7 (Box 37, Folder 891)
        For collaboration with Benny Baker
      - The Last Ship From Europe ( Der letzte Schiff von Europa ): contract, 1939 Aug 29 (Box 37, Folder 892)
      - The Silent Tree: contracts, 1943-44 (Box 37, Folder 893)
        For collaboration with Harry J. Essex
      - The Tin Cup ( House Without Windows )
        - Contracts, 1952-58 (Box 37, Folder 894-895)
        - Correspondence, 1952-58, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 896-902)
        - Statements, 1952-59 (Box 37, Folder 903)
        - Program, 1957 (Box 37, Folder 904)
        - Reviews and publicity, 1956-57 (Box 37, Folder 905)
    - Reich, Richard and Alden Nash
      - Three Mothers: contracts, 1947-48 (Box 37, Folder 906)
    - Rice, Elmer L.
      - Counselor-At-Law: contracts, 1933-38 (Box 37, Folder 907)
      - Street Scene: contract, 1938 Aug 31 (Box 37, Folder 908)
    - Ries, Estelle H.
      - Contract: general, 1940 Sep 27 (Box 37, Folder 909)
    - Rieseberg, Harry E.
      - Contracts: general, 1941-42 (Box 37, Folder 910)
      - Correspondence: general, 1959-60 (Box 37, Folder 911-913)
        See also: Oversize, Box 52, folder 1262
      - I Dive for Treasure (book)
        - Contracts, 1941 (Box 37, Folder 914)
        - Statements, 1951-58 (Box 37, Folder 915)
    - Rockey, Ordean
      - Facin' Front and Sudler: contract, 1937 Aug 23 (Box 37, Folder 916)
    - Rodgers, Richard and Lorenz Hart
      - I Married an Angel: statements, 1953-54 (Box 37, Folder 917)
    - Roessler, Carl
      - Die fünf Frankfurter: contract, 1930 Sep 9 (Box 37, Folder 918)
    - Rogoff, Gregor
      - Die kollektive Kuh: contracts, 1934 Nov 19 (Box 38, Folder 919)
    - Romains, Jules
      - Doctor Knock ( Knock )
        - Correspondence, 1951-58 (Box 38, Folder 920-923)
        - Statements, 1951-54 (Box 38, Folder 924)
    - Ross, George and Dorothy Ross
      - Keep Up With the Joneses: contracts, 1943 (Box 38, Folder 925)
        Incl: contracts for adaptation by Jerry Horwin
    - Rubinstein, Ema
      - Contract: general, 1923 Oct 12 (Box 38, Folder 926)
    - Rubio, Emery and Miriam Balf
      - The First Stone: contract, 1945 Feb 13 (Box 38, Folder 927)
      - Sunday Breakfast
        - Contracts, 1948-53 (Box 38, Folder 928-929)
        - Correspondence, 1955-57 (Box 38, Folder 930)
        - Statements, 1950-58 (Box 38, Folder 931)
      - This Here Emerson
        - Contract, 1954 Aug 3 (Box 38, Folder 932)
        - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 38, Folder 933)
        - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 38, Folder 934)
          Incl: John C. Foreman, Shepard Traube
        - Correspondence, 1956-57 (Box 38, Folder 935)
    - Rumbold, Zoe Akins
      - Human Element: contracts, 1937-38 (Box 38, Folder 936)
        Based on the work by W. Somerset Maugham. Incl: contract for adaptation by László (Ladislas) Bús-Fekete
    - Sainges, Dorothy
      - The Pond Lilies: contract, 1938 Nov 7 (Box 38, Folder 937)
    - Salten, Felix
      - Pietro erregt Aufsehen (novel): contracts, 1937-38 (Box 38, Folder 938)
      - Sträfling nummer 33 (novel): contracts, 1937-38 (Box 38, Folder 939)
    - Schary, Dore
      - Violence: contracts, 1936-37, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 940)
    - Schlüter, Karl
      - Derailed ( Entgleist ): contracts, 1932 (Box 39, Folder 941)
    - Schulz-Breiden, Eugen
      - Contract: general, 1937 Nov 13 (Box 39, Folder 942)
    - Scribe, [Eugène?] and [Ernest?] Legouvé
      - Bataille de dames: contract, 1940 Mar 28 (Box 39, Folder 943)
    - Selous, W. George
      - Katzenzungen: contracts, 1935 (Box 39, Folder 944)
    - Shale, Harry and Louis Sunshine
      - Lady By Name ( Kitten ): contracts, 1942-46 (Box 39, Folder 945)
    - Sherwood, Robert E.
      - Idiot's Delight: contract, 1936 Sep 22 (Box 39, Folder 946)
    - Shinkman, Paul A.
      - Petty Round: contract, 1939 Oct 11 (Box 39, Folder 947)
    - Shishmariov, Kyril, Harry Tierney, and Raymond Egan
      - Holiday From Heaven: contract, 1945 May 15 (Box 39, Folder 948)
    - Sil-Vara, G. A.
      - Contracts: general, 1929-30 (Box 39, Folder 949)
      - Brand im Schloss: contract, 1929 Jun 1 (Box 39, Folder 950)
    - Simkhovitch, B.K.
      - Contracts: general, 1940-41 (Box 39, Folder 951)
      - The Playboy From Newark: contracts, 1941-42 (Box 39, Folder 952)
    - Smith, Earl Hobson and Louise McCamy[?]
      - Stephen Foster: contract, 1934 Oct 26 (Box 39, Folder 953)
    - Solt, Andrew
      - The Beggar and the Queen's Daughter: contracts, 1939 (Box 39, Folder 954)
      - Radium: contract, 1939 Apr 5 (Box 39, Folder 955)
        Collaboration agreement with Barre Dunbar
      - Your Picture Please: contract, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 956)
    - Solt, Andrew and Stefan Bekeffi
      - Accidents Don't Happen ( Es gibt keine Zufaelle ): contracts, 1938-40 (Box 39, Folder 957)
    - Solt, Andrew and Iván Tors
      - Lázálom: contract, 1940 Feb 9 (Box 39, Folder 958)
    - Solt, Andrew and Wesley Towner
      - "Rock-a-Bye Baby" ("synopsis for a motion picture story"): contract, 1939 (Box 39, Folder 959)
    - Spicer, Clayton and Harold Winston
      - Tightrope: contract, 1951 Jan 8 (Box 39, Folder 960)
    - Spina, Harold, Walter Hannan, and Edward Heyman
      - Stovepipe Hat